Tom Moore

Senior Frontend & Full-stack Developer

tommoore.dev@gmail.com

07850682438

Manchester

linkedin.com/in/tom-moore96

Senior Frontend developer with 6 years' experience, always looking to build better, cleaner, more reliable software.

SKILLS

 React.js
 Next.js
 TypeScript
 Tanstack
 Redux
 Agile
 React Testing Library
 Vite
 AWS
 Lambda

 Jest
 Node
 React Native
 Vue
 Webpack
 Communication
 Python
 Selenium
 MySQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Crowdcube

12/2022 - 10/2024 Manchester

Investment platform

Achievements/Tasks

- Led development of the new investor portfolio, creating a beta version to slowly transition users to the new portfolio as it became more feature rich.
- Upgraded our tech stack by migrating custom patterns to the NextJS pages router, significantly improving the frontend architecture.
- Mentored less experienced developers, I involved them in decision making and encouraged them to take on more challenging work, advising them and pair programming where needed.
- Been an active member of the growth squad and organising breakout meetings to brainstorm new ideas that increase revenue
 and prioritise them based on development complexity.

Contact: Dave Halsey - david.halsey@crowdcube.com

Fullstack Developer

Koodoo

10/2021 - 12/2022 Manchester

Mortgage comparison

Achievements/Tasks

- Led on project to create a common components library to be used across multiple teams.
- Introduced new technologies & practices to the company such as TypeScript, microfrontends and Styled Components.
- Improved test coverage on legacy code to > 90% in areas I worked on and maintained 100% test coverage on all new components made.
- Mentored developers and gave presentations to share knowledge and improve standards within the company.
- Maintained backend written in Express.

Contact: Matthew Peel - matthew.peel@koodoo.io

Frontend Developer

Moneysupermarket

04/2021 - December Manchester

Achievements/Tasks

- Built flexible component microservices in Vue to be consumed by our CMS.
- Created a CLI with Node to aid developers on our team in quickly creating microservice deployment configurations. The CLI
 would give the developer options and ask questions about the microservice that was being deployed.
- Rebranding MSM website in accordance with Zeplin designs and liaising with the content team to plan microservice api design.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer (React)

i6 Group

03/2020 - 04/2021



The world's leading digital fuel management platform for the aviation industry.

Achievements/Tasks

- Managed the integration of existing React apps into an existing product using micro-frontends (single-spa, systemjs). Thus
 giving the customer the feeling of using a single application for multiple tasks and products, yet still allowing the development
 teams to work and deploy independently of each other.
- Authored the i6 Frontend Styleguide. Upon joining i6 I noticed onboarding and documentation needed improvement, so I took
 it upon myself to write a frontend code styleguide for upcoming members to settle in more easily and more comfortably; and
 for existing developers to propose new patterns/styles/technologies.
- Built a testing playground to help the team decide which testing framework was best for ourselves. When we were struggling
 to see the pros/cons between React Testing Library and Enzyme, I used the discussion/confusion as an opportunity to improve
 my testing skills and demonstrate the differences of the two technologies (both syntactically and philosophically) to the rest of
 the frontend team.
- Introduced React Hooks to the business to bring them up to date with modern practices. This reduced our reliance on Redux, reduced the amount of duplicated code, and made it easier for less experienced developers.

Frontend Developer (React Native)

School Spider

04/2019 - 03/2020 Manchester

Creating software for schools to manage their website (news/blogs/images etc.) and solutions for school - parent interaction.

Achievements/Tasks

- Created an app for parents to book parents evening appointments, school trips, fill out forms and surveys; as well as view news, blogs, galleries, notifications and communicate via forums in under a year.
- Taught myself React Native from scratch in order to build the app, I also learnt how to use Google and Apple's developer consoles to deploy the app.
- Introduced React Hooks to the business to bring them up to date with modern practices.
- Worked with React, Redux, Redux-Saga and TailwindCSS before jumping at the opportunity to learn and work with React Native.

Junior Frontend Developer

Picker

04/2018 - 04/2019 Barcelona, Spain

A place to share your favourite products with everyone so that we don't buy more, but better.

Achievements/Tasks

- Reduced loading speeds on homepage by more than 60% by implementing lazy loading functionality and working closely with the CTO to change the way data is structured and used.
- Received a strong introduction to Agile methodologies. The CTO was very passionate about Agile and instilled this passion in me as well.
- Built software to be used by CEO and CFO to manage and analyse data on successful products and influencers.
- Independently managed and updated the entire web app while the CTO was developing the mobile app.

Contact: Conan Moriarty - conanm@gmail.com

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Live Music Reading Cooking Languages History TV & Film Built Environment Cycling

EDUCATION

O Full Stack Software Development Course Codeworks



Barcelona

About

12/2017 - 04/2018

I chose this bootcamp as it was the most intensive in Europe. After completing 3 technical tests and a pre-course I had to spend 12 hours a day, 6 days a week for 12 weeks on campus, I'm not exaggerating. There was a lot of hands on work and few lectures, I think the most valuable skill I had learnt was how to teach myself and be confident enough to push through hard times. Codeworks gave me the perfect foundation to grow over the next 3 years as a software developer.

